(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Ina'nis.
She spent her days singing by the lake.
But one day,
She woke up somewhere else.
透き通る　季節が好き
I love the clear seasons
風がまた　熱を連れてくる
The wind brings back the heat once more
何千回も巡って　何万回も輝く
Orbiting thousands of times, shining tens of thousands of times
そうやって　光が生まれる
That's how light is born
イノセント・ブルー ～ version de l'apprivoiser ～
Innocent Blue ~version de l'apprivoiser~
Lyrics: こだまさおり　Music: 神前 暁 (MONACA)
Lyrics: Saori Kodama  Music: Satoru Kosaki (MONACA)
陽射しが溶けてる　空の向こう
The sunlight is melting beyond the sky
どこまでも　透明な青
A transparent blue that goes on forever
スピードを上げた
I picked up the speed
イノセント・ブルー ～ version de l'apprivoiser
Innocent Blue ~ version de l'apprivoiser
思い立ち
Having made up my mind
自分の意志で
By my own will
今　飛び立つの
I'm taking flight now
感じている
I can feel it
無邪気な誓い
An innocent vow
言葉は知らない
I don't know the words
流れていく
Flowing away
水の行方に
To where the water goes
心を馳せよ
Let your heart wander
透き通る季節が過ぎ
The transparent season passes
風が待つ熱を連れてくる
Bringing the heat the wind awaits
傷跡は消えていったわ
The scars have faded away
溢れ出す情熱のシンフォニー
An overflowing symphony of passion
何千回も巡って
Going around thousands of times
何万回も輝く
Shining tens of thousands of times
そうやって光が生まれる
That is how light is born
忘れじの言の葉
The Forgotten Words
言の葉を紡いで
Weaving words together
まどろんだうたかた
Bubbles in a slumber
旅人迷い込む
A traveler wanders in
おとぎの深い霧
The deep mist of a fairy tale
差しのべた手のひら
An outstretched palm
そっと触れる予感
A premonition of a gentle touch
受け止めて零れた
Caught and spilled over
光の一滴
A single drop of light
La la la...
面影うつろって
Traces fading away
追憶はまぼろし
Recollections are but an illusion
想いの果てる場所
The place where feelings end
まだ遥か遠くて
Is still far, far away
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering
やがて謳われて幾千幾万幾億の
Eventually sung by thousands, millions, billions
旋律となる
It becomes a melody
いつか失い奪われて
Some day lost and snatched away
消える定めでもそれは忘れられることなき物語
Even if destined to vanish, it is a story that will never be forgotten
指先を絡めて
Entwining fingertips
触れる誰かの夢
Touching someone's dream
刻まれた想いの
Of the feelings carved in
こだまだけが響く
Only the echoes resound
言の葉を紡いで
Weaving words together
まどろんだうたかた
Bubbles in a slumber
旅人の名前を
A traveler's name
おとぎ話という
Called a fairy tale
求め探して彷徨って
Seeking, searching, and wandering
やがて道となり幾千幾万幾億の
Eventually becoming a path for thousands, millions, billions
英雄はゆく
Heroes march on
いつか失い奪われて
Some day lost and snatched away
消える定めでもそれは忘れられることなくここにある
Even if destined to vanish, it will never be forgotten, it is right here
狂い迷って　やがて戯れて
Wandering in madness, eventually frolicking,
幾千に組み　幾億の旋律となる
combining in thousands, becoming a melody of hundreds of millions.
いつか失い　奪われて消える定めでも
Even if it is a fate that will one day be lost, stolen and vanished,
それは忘れられることなき物語
it is a story that can never be forgotten.
君の中にある赤と青の線
The red and blue lines inside you,
それらが結ばれるのは心の臓
they connect at the heart.
風の中でも負けないような声で
With a voice that won't lose even to the wind,
届ける言葉を今は育ててる
I'm nurturing the words to deliver now.
時は枕木
Time is a crosstie,
風は二肌
wind is soft skin,
星は産土
stars are the guardian deities,
人は陽炎
people are heat haze.
なんで泣いてるの　と聞かれ答えれる
Asked why I'm crying, I can answer,
涙なんかじゃ　僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるで
with just tears, it doesn't at all catch up to the meaning of our meeting,
追いつかない　この身一つじゃ足りない叫び
a scream that isn't enough with just this one body.
君の手に触れた時にだけ震えた心があったよ
There was a heart that only trembled when it touched your hand.
意味を幾つ越えれば　僕らは辿り着けるのかな
I wonder how many meanings we must cross to arrive.
愚かさでいい　醜さでいい
Foolishness is fine, ugliness is fine,
正しさのその先で　君と手を取りたい
beyond righteousness, I want to take your hand.
なんで泣いてるの　と聞かれ答えれる
Asked why I'm crying, I can answer,
涙なんかじゃ　僕ら出会えたことの意味にはまるで
with just tears, it doesn't at all catch up to the meaning of our meeting,
追いつかない　この身一つじゃ足りない叫び
a scream that isn't enough with just this one body.
君の手に触れた時にだけ震えた心があったよ
There was a heart that only trembled when it touched your hand.
意味を幾つ越えれば　僕らは辿り着けるのかな
I wonder how many meanings we must cross to arrive.
愚かさでいい　醜さでいい　正しさのその先で
Foolishness is fine, ugliness is fine, beyond righteousness...
いざその先で
Now, beyond that,
君と生きていきたい
I want to live with you.
Wow!
Hello, everyone!
Good morning, afternoon, evening!
How are you guys doing?
Good, good.
Are we all miraculously pres...
I can't talk.
Are we all miraculously present?
Yay!
I can hear you guys!
Yay, yay, Ina, wah, wah!
Wah-hi!
Good to see you guys!
Welcome to my birthday live!
We made it in time this year!
Let's go!
And of course, don't forget to,
you know, talk about it,
take screenshots, you know,
share it with everyone
using the hashtag over here.
♪♪♪
Yeah!
So that I can also, you know, read what you guys
have thought about while watching the stream and stuff.
And yeah!
Of course, you know, let us talk about...
Where are we?
I just went through a door
and suddenly we ended up in this...
I don't know, it almost looks like we're inside
a storybook or something.
I have no idea where we are.
But you know what?
We're gonna roll with it,
'cause that's what we do.
And of course,
let us not forget...
my clothes also changed!
Look! Do I look cute?
Wow!
And of course, you know, look at all the details!
My flaps have gone longer.
I have this cool gauntlet now.
Look at this!
Wah, I feel like a knight.
I feel like I can defeat all evil.
And of course I got my, I don't know,
three glass pens behind me.
Wow! I wonder if this is my weapon.
I can poke people with my glass pens.
And all the details on the dress!
Isn't it beautiful?
And look, my skirt is actually made out of
Takodachis!
Ooh! That's right.
I know, so I can already see it,
you know, you guys are going,
"Oh, Ina, that's me, that's me!"
But yeah, look at this beautiful, beautiful outfit.
Of course, I gotta thank Kuroboshi-papa
for designing this wonderful, wonderful outfit.
Thank you, Kuroboshi-papa!
You're always the best at making the outfits.
So, yeah!
And you know, I want to talk about a lot of things,
but it is my birthday,
and I'm gonna go have fun around here.
I don't know where we are,
but you know, I'm gonna go look around
and see where we end up.
We'll see, I don't know.
Maybe we'll find something fun to do.
But yeah, you know,
I guess I'll see you guys around.
Take care!
Oh, what is this place?
I don't know. Do they have food around here? Hmm.
こ、え、え、こ…
Co, eh, eh, co...
あ、アキ先輩じゃないですか！
Oh, isn't it Aki-senpai!
お、イナ！
Oh, Ina!
アキ、イナ…
Aki, Ina...
え、なんで石になってたんですか？
Eh, why was I turned into stone?
ここ、おん、あれ？
Here, um, that?
なんか影があったような気がして、
I felt like there was a shadow,
気づいたらこんな、待ってたんですけど…
and before I knew it, this... I was waiting, but...
イナ！
Ina!
はい！
Yes!
どこ、ここ？
Where is this?
私も知らないんです。
I don't know either.
イナも知らないの！？
Ina doesn't know either!?
はい。
Yes.
なんか急に、なんかドアにヒュッとしたら、
Suddenly, I went through a door,
衣装もこれになったし、
and my outfit changed to this,
ここ、どこか知らない。
and I don't know where this is.
イナ、かわいい！
Ina, you're cute!
新衣装、そうです。
New outfit, yes.
可愛いでしょ！
It's cute, right!
めっちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
よく見せて、よく見せて！
Show me well, show me well!
可愛い、可愛い！
Cute, cute!
いや、でも、ここ、なんか全然知らない場所で、
No, but, being in this place I don't know at all,
アキ先輩がいて、なんか嬉しい！
and having Aki-senpai here, I'm kind of happy!
本当？そう。
Really? I see.
えー、アキロゼも、このね、3Dの姿で
Eh, AkiRose is also actually happy
イナとこうやって会えたの、実は嬉しい。
to be able to meet Ina like this in this 3D form.
嬉しい！
I'm happy!
実は私、あの、アキ先輩といつか、
Actually, I, um, wanted to
あの、歌ったり、踊ったり、やりたかったんです。
um, sing and dance with Aki-senpai someday.
えっ、じゃあ、もしかして一緒に今日は歌えるの？
Wait, does that mean we can sing together today?
いいんですか？
Is it okay?
いい、歌おうよ！
Yes, let's sing!
やったー！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
じゃあ、どの曲がいいかな？
Then, which song should we do?
ふむふむ、ホロライブの曲もあるしね、色々。
Hmm, there are various Hololive songs too.
そうですね。でも、なんか、先輩の曲の中で一番、一番好きな曲は...
Right. But, my absolute favorite among your songs, Senpai...
やっぱり、あの曲ですね。
Is definitely that one.
え？あれ？
Eh? That one?
あれですね。
That one.
えー？でもわかんないな。言ってくんないと。
Eh? But I don't know. You have to tell me.
あれですね、アキ先輩がこう、あ、あ、あ...
It's the one where Aki-senpai goes like, ah, ah, ah...
見れる、ちょっとセクシー、セクシーダンス。
Where we can see your slightly sexy dance.
セクシーダンスはいっぱいある？
There are lots of sexy dances?
あ、いっぱいじゃないか（笑）
Wait, maybe not that many (laughs).
でも、でも、なんかアキ先輩だったらこの曲ですね。
But, for Aki-senpai, it has to be this song.
じゃあ、今日は一緒にシャルイース、いいんですか？
Then, Shallrys together today? Is that okay?
歌お、イナ。
Let's sing, Ina.
はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'm in your hands!
嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
シャルイース、イナとこうやって歌うのも初めてだもんね。
It's the first time singing Shallrys with you like this, Ina.
そうですね。なんかライブとかあんまり機会がなくて、うん。
True. There haven't been many chances at lives and such.
やっと、やっと、やっと！嬉しい、嬉しい！
Finally, finally, finally! So happy!
じゃあ、アキロゼのシャルイースはなんといってもアキロゼの国の伝承歌。
Well, Akirose's Shallrys is the traditional song of Akirose's country.
だから、まあ何か、イナの助けになることがあるかもしれないし。
So, it might be able to help you in some way, Ina.
一緒に歌ってパワーをね、つけてもらいたいなと思うから。
I want you to gain power by singing it together.
頑張ろう！
Let's do our best!
はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'm in your hands!
ああ、ドキドキする！
Ah, my heart's racing!
はい、じゃあ行きましょうか。
Okay, shall we go?
こっちこっちこっちこっち...
This way, this way...
頑張るぞ！はい。
Let's do our best! Yes.
Gontas halelia on Shallys
Alimita potimai jilique
Seclocs ocnocala stinoketing
Hapua mukil Shallbeil
シャルイース / Lyrics: as Music, Arrangement: kotoki
Shallrys / Lyrics: as Music, Arrangement: kotoki
Yae di lirae eminasaktier
Dignae eminasurigatoria
Nessil dinas wenavel ticas
Dimioras morofua apua
Gontas halelia on Shallys
Alimita potimai jilique
Alumiatulos lulia
Dontokias tulia
Gontas halelia on Shallys
Animita potimai jilique
Seclocs ocnocala stinoketing
Hapua mukil Shallbeil
Etu daligali biria
Falados lumia dislamo
Gulos uinia minai tulique
Menelas muo kloruru
Dinlaru bipuru notomuru
Farumai viralemuseturi
Onomadovanilo undarune
Dinawias salame de kantomiralira
シャルイース
Shaly's
Oh firasimi ya
Oh, my dear friend
Vimora sheronikon ya
I will sing a song
Imi opuro pomeno ona
In this beautiful world
Vimora sheron o ra...
I will sing a song...
Kon to areriuya o sharunizu
Let's celebrate Shaly's with hallelujahs
Animunita fopi ma i churi
As the light shines upon us
Zikusu onokure shinokeshin
Flowers are blooming
Abo amyuki nosharu veiru
The breeze blows softly
Morupesen to morashekanto
Dancing and singing
Mi foinas morohu ho ra
Forever in this world
Mi foinas morohu ho...
Forever in this world...
クロイウタ
Lyrics: 菊地はな Music: 岡部啓一
Black Song
Lyrics: Hana Kikuchi Music: Keiichi Okabe
躍らせり
Set to dance
破滅の歌
The song of ruin
獣となり
Becoming a beast
鬨斬り
Cutting through battle cries
奪い去る
Snatched away
針の調べ
The melody of the needles
輪廻の火と
With the fire of samsara
足り
It is enough
千羽羽ばたき
Flapping of a thousand wings
濃い紅　白柄
Deep crimson, white handle
いつ終わるともなき
With no end in sight
声　天命　記録　奪わね
Voice, destiny, record, do not snatch them away
ささめく
Whispering
クロイハナ
Black Flower
あの声が
That voice
壊れた目の
Of broken eyes
アルマ
Alma
クロイハナ
Black Flower
あの歌が
That song
作り舞いず
Creates
アルマ
Alma
意味
Meaning
クロイウタ
Black Song
あたらせり　こおりあううた
Our frozen voices entwine
あくむなまうひを
On the day nightmares dance
うとうたちきるしが
A song to sever the cycle
いくあかいもりから
From the deep red forest
いむべくけがれあらむよわいあの
That cursed, defiled, and fragile...
おもいはがれる
...memory peels away
くろいはな
Black flower
あのこえが
That voice
いのりのちが
The blood of prayer
あるまま
As it is
くろいはな
Black flower
あのうたら
That song
ざんげのひが
The light of penitence
あるまま
As it is
きえ
Fading
さいあくは
The worst
まちおりる
Descends
こわれたとき
When time breaks
ひとゆめ
A single dream
くりかえり
Repeats
わかれゆき
Departing
ゆるされざる
Unforgiven
おとはな
Sound and flower
しう
Falling death
storia
Lyrics, Music: 梶浦由記
Lyrics, Music: Yuki Kajiura
秘密の黄昏に　君の手を取った
I took your hand in the secret twilight
古のバラッド　繰り返すように
As if repeating an ancient ballad
紡ぐ
We weave
Romans of love
君のことを　いつも歌いたい
I want to sing of you forever
哀しい夜を　温もりで満たして
Filling the sad night with warmth
愛を見つけて
Find love
雛菊が咲いてた
Daisies were blooming
白い月輝いてた
The white moon was shining
君の囁きで
With your whisper
始まるよ　永久の
It begins, the eternal...
storia...
Voci di me a storia
水のなか 静かに 澄んでゆく
In the water, it quietly becomes clear
懐かしい 恋の物語
A nostalgic tale of love
光と影の中から
From within the light and shadows
愛しさは生まれて
Love is born
帰る
And returns
Kaji di mia solitu...
君の目を見ていた
I was looking into your eyes
Ambe miya savitu...
その腕の中で
Within those arms
恋人のささやき
The whispers of lovers
星屑の散った
Scattered stardust
いにしえのバラード
An ancient ballad
泉を満たして
Filling the spring
風は 西へ
The wind blows West
優しい歌を君と歌いたい
I want to sing a gentle song with you
五月の月が今ここにある
The May moon is here now
恋の歌が今宵響くから
For a love song echoes tonight
冷たい胸を温もりで満たして
Filling the cold heart with warmth
語ろう
Let's tell...
愛の storia
The story of love
Ambe miya savitu...
あれ？大丈夫？大丈夫ですか？
Huh? Are you okay? Are you alright?
あれ？動ける！動ける！動けるぞ！
Huh? I can move! I can move! I can move!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
動けるってなったね。いつも通り。よかったー。
We can move again. Back to normal. Thank goodness.
いつものやつだ！
It's the usual thing!
また動けるようになったぞ。
We can move again!
いやー、助かった。イナちゃんが助けてくれたやつ？
Man, that was a lifesaver. Is this what Ina-chan saved us with?
なんか、なんとかぴょんしたら動けるようになって。嬉しい。よかった。
Well, somehow after jumping around I could move again. I'm so happy. Thank goodness.
やったー！やったー！動けたー！
Yay! Yay! We can move!
なんで石になってたんですか？
Why were you turned into stone?
なんでだっけ？
Why was it again?
なんかね、なんか見たよね？
Well, we saw something, right?
なんかいた。なんかいたんだよ。
Something was there. Something was definitely there.
翼が... ふわーっとなってたから...
Wings... they were all fluttery...
竜っぽかったかな？
Was it like a dragon?
竜？ドラゴン？
A dragon? Dragon?
竜っぽかったかな。竜っぽかった気はするけど...
I think it was dragon-like. It felt like a dragon, but...
もうわかんなくなっちゃった。覚えてない。ごめんごめん。覚えてないけど...
I don't know anymore. I don't remember. Sorry, sorry. I don't remember, but...
そういえば、イナちゃん！
By the way, Ina-chan!
はい！
Yes!
あなた、誕生日じゃない！
It's your birthday, isn't it!
そうです、誕生日です！
That's right, it's my birthday!
おめでとうー！！
Happy Birthday!!
いやー、大好きな二人と一緒って嬉しい。
I'm so happy to be with two people I love so much.
照れるー！嬉しい！嬉しい！
That's embarrassing! We're happy too! So happy!
なんかイナちゃんとね、五期生はね、言ったらデビュー日近かったもんね。
Well, Ina-chan and Gen 5, our debut dates were pretty close, weren't they?
そうですね。1ヶ月... 1ヶ月ぐらいだったから。
That's right. About a month... it was only about a month apart.
なんかもう同期、同期。同期。
It's like we're batchmates, batchmates. Batchmates.
えへへ、同期。同期みたいな感じだから。
Ehehe, batchmates. Because it feels like we're in the same generation.
嬉しい。そうです。でも、ししわたと歌う機会があんまりなくて。
I'm happy. That's right. But I haven't had many chances to sing with ShishiWata.
ね、なかったから。
Yeah, we haven't.
今回なんか、いや、いつでも、いつか、なんか、わため先輩とししろんと歌いたいんだって。
This time... well, I've always wanted to sing with Watame-senpai and Shishiron someday.
セットいいんですか？
Is it okay if we're a set?
嬉しいね！嬉しいね！バリバリ嬉しいね！
We're happy too! So happy! Super happy!
二人の歌声めちゃめちゃだいだいだいだい大好きなので、嬉しい。
I love your singing voices so, so, so much, so I'm happy.
ありがとう。うちらもだいだいだい大好きだよ！
Thank you. We love you so much too!
いや、私の方が好きだから。
No, I love her more.
いやいや、わための方が好きだから。
No, no, Watame loves her more.
いや、私の方が好きだから。
No, I love her more.
やめてよ！
Stop it!
私の方がだいだいだいだい好きだから！どっちが好きなの！？わーー！
I love her so, so, so much! Who do you love more!? Waaah!
大好きだわー
I love it!
嬉しい
I'm happy!
二人、大好き
I love you two!
でもイナちゃん、なんか服が可愛くなってない？
But Ina-chan, hasn't your outfit become cuter?
そうですね、なんか...
That's right, somehow...
可愛いー
Cute!
なんかドアがあって、
There was this door,
ドアをピョーンとしたらこの衣装になりました。
and when I went through it, I changed into this outfit.
へー、可愛いー
Wow, so cute!
似合ってる
It suits you.
よく見たらさ、タコダチ...
If you look closely, the Takodachis...
ねー、タコダチがいっぱいですよ、これ。
Right, there are lots of Takodachis on this.
これ、いっぱいおるんやな
There really are a lot of them here.
いたるところに...
They're everywhere...
靴も、タコダチなの、可愛くない？
Even the shoes are Takodachis, aren't they cute?
あ、本当だ、タコダチだ、可愛い
Ah, you're right, they are Takodachis! Cute!
おしゃれだねー
Very stylish.
いいねー
It's nice.
いやー、でも嬉しい
Wow, I'm just so happy.
うぅー、嬉しいー、
Uuu, I'm happy,
うぅー、あっという間に...
uuu, in the blink of an eye...
いい言葉がわかんない、嬉しいー
I can't find the words, I'm just so happy.
嬉しいー
We're happy too.
こちらこそだよ
The pleasure is ours.
あ、どめ、
Ah, wait,
え、あなた、ちょっと時間があれじゃないの？
hey, you, isn't your time almost up?
え、もう時間？あ、やばいやばい
Eh, already? Ah, oh no, oh no!
え？
Eh?
はっ！もう行かなきゃかも
Ah! I might have to go already.
え、ハバナの収録、あなたあるんじゃないの？
Wait, don't you have a recording for Havana?
やばいやばい、飛行機乗らなきゃ
Oh no, oh no, I have to catch a plane!
ちょっと飛行機乗って行かなきゃだから、イナ、またね！
I have to go catch a plane, so, Ina, see you later!
バイバイ、後でね
Bye-bye, see you later!
ありがとうー！バイバイー！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
なんか、なんかおるぞ、なんだあれ？
Wait, something's there. What is that?
なんだこれ、気になるなー
What is this? I'm curious.
急げ急げ、あ、急がなきゃ
Hurry, hurry! Ah, I have to hurry.
Ah... that was so fun!
Ooooh... I got to finally sing with Shishiron,
and of course with Watame-senpai. I'm so, so happy, you know?
Huh... they did say they saw something like a dragon? A dragon...?
But uh... after all this singing, I'm guess...
But uh... after all this singing, I guess...
I'm kind of, kind of getting sleepy.
So, I'm just... just gonna take a... small nap, okay?
I'm gonna take a small nap. So... okay.
Yeah... I'll just go, go...
とある竜の恋の歌 / Lyrics, Music: 江幡育子
Toaru Ryuu no Koi no Uta / Lyrics, Music: Ikuko Ebata
音の無い大地に
In a land without sound
恋の歌 響けば
If the song of love resounds
狂い出す歯車
The gears start to go mad
止められぬ宿命が
The unstoppable fate
弾けた
Has burst forth
蘇る
Awakening
今
Now
いにしえより千紀
Thousands of years since ancient times
漠の恋目覚めた
The love of the desert has awakened
絆を求めて
Seeking the bond
焔は迸る
The flames gush out
破壊と再生
Destruction and rebirth
気高き君の呪縛
Your noble spell
透き通る魂
A transparent soul
嘘もなく気高く
Noble and without lies
原罪を抱えて
Carrying the original sin
理屈無き恋求む
Seeking love without reason
愚かさ
Foolishness
月明かり
Moonlight
今
Now
二人照らす
Illuminating the two of us
刹那の時 重ねた
Overlapping moments of time
絆の行方を
The whereabouts of the bond
両手で抱きしめた
I held tight with both hands
終わりと始まり
The end and the beginning
尊き君の記憶
Your precious memories
絆を求めて
Seeking bonds
焔はほとばしる
Flames gush forth
殺意と再生
Malice and rebirth
気高き君の呪縛
The spell of your noble self
絆の行方を
The whereabouts of bonds
両手で抱きしめた
I held tight with both hands
終わりと始まり
The end and the beginning
尊き君の記憶
The memory of your precious self
カイネ/救済
Kainé / Salvation
Shul faram o heen
Ar charuk no seen
Da galek tye foor
Ma lek voy de as la theren spoor
Yo dante rehadre kena laik
Volo liya boyo
Migenda yakrokeno hey
Kaine ra kola
Shul faram o heen
Ar charuk no seen
Da galek tye foor
Ma lek voy de as la theren spoor
Yo dante rehadre kena laik
Volo liya boyo
Migenda yakrokeno hey
Yo mo tei ko mi ren talha
Vai ra chu
時の揺り籠で
In the cradle of time,
冷たい夢を見る
I dream a cold dream.
君が歌ってくれた
The gentle, gentle lullaby
優しい、優しい子守唄
that you sang for me.
Synchronicity~第三章 巡る世界のレクイエム~
Synchronicity ~Chapter 3: Requiem for the Cycling World~
君が望んだのは
What you desired was
終わらぬ世界
a never-ending world.
俺が望むのは
What I desire is
世界の終わり
the end of the world.
選ばれし声は
The chosen voices
迷い、憂い、死を唄う
sing of hesitation, sorrow, and death.
悲しみを
Changing sadness
喜びに
into joy.
苦しみを
Changing suffering
笑顔に変えて
into smiles.
報われずに
Without being rewarded,
君は朽ちていくの?
will you rot away?
共に耐え
Enduring together,
救い、この世界
save this world.
ただ君だけ
Only for you,
想いは
our thoughts
交わらない
will never meet.
巡り巡る命は
Life that goes round and round,
世界にこの手で
with these hands,
安らぎと祝福を
give peace and blessings to the world.
終わらせたい
I want to end this.
届かない願いは
A wish that doesn't reach,
虚しさだけを残して
leaving only emptiness behind.
始まる
Beginning
奈落へ
toward the abyss,
全てを終わらせるため
to bring everything to an end.
悲しみ、苦しみ、幸せさえも
Even sadness, suffering, and happiness,
抗えない定めを
this irresistible fate,
今、解き放つ
I release it now.
君が望んだのは
What you desired was
俺が望んだのは
What I desired was
残された声は
The voices left behind
嘆き君を想いながら
grieve while thinking of you.
一人君のために歌う
Alone, I sing for you.
一人君のために...
Alone, for you...
巡り巡る命は
Life that goes round and round,
世界にこの手で
with these hands,
安らぎと祝福を
give peace and blessings to the world.
定めを奪い
Taking away fate,
この身は
this body,
君とならどこまでも
if with you, will go anywhere.
照らして
Shine upon us
永遠に続く歌を
with a song that lasts forever.
光を
Light,
定めを
fate,
今、解き放て
I release it now.
光の底に
At the bottom of light,
眠れ
sleep.
Bae, are you okay?
Ahhh! My knight! Finally you've come!
Seriously, I waited like 100 years, man. What took you so long?
100... 100 years?
Wait, hold on, hold on.
How... Google, how long does a rat live?
Man! Oh my... oh my muscles!
Oh, they're so rigid from being stuck as a statue.
Thank you so much for saving me.
Don't worry. You know what? You know?
Ina the Hero is here to save you.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah.
We defeated the evil trash can!
Save the rat!
I don't know if you guys saw, but there was an evil dragon and he was like...
SAVE THE RAT!
Yeah! How dare they.
Are you okay? Are you okay? All good, all good, thank you, thank you.
Yeah. Now that you're all well, you might as well say the thing.
Eh? Say the thing?
You know, the thing. The thing.
What thing?
You know... Like today is a special day?
Oh! Yeah! Today is... Today is the day...
...that the princess has been saved! Thank you very much! Thank you!
拍手、拍手、はい！ あざます、あざます！ はい、はい、あざます！
Clap, clap, yes! Thanks a lot, thanks a lot! Yes, yes, thanks a lot!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Bae! What day is when this purple one become to be? Purple-born-day-day?
Oh! I see! You're looking for that one! Yeah, yeah, okay, okay, okay!
INA-CHAN, HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
Yay! Thanks for joining me today, Bae!
Thanks for inviting me!
I was so happy! It was so fun, so fun!
Oh yeah, it was so fun to dance with you and sing with you. It's the best! It's the best!
Yes! I just wanted to say, Ina, your new outfit is so cute!
Thank you! You like it? It's so cute! Oh my god!
It's called... What's the outfit called?
勇者！
The Hero!
Yuusha Ina! Oh!
That's right! I look like a hero, right?
You do look like a hero! My hero!
Ooh! Ah, Bae!
And Mr. Squeaks, thanks for leading me to Bae!
Thanks man! You did great! High five! High five!
Man, if it wasn't for him, I'd be stuck as a statue forever.
Don't shake your head too much, he's gonna fly off!
He's used to it! We're just like... Oh no! There we go. He's all good.
Oh yeah, thank you Bae for joining, it was so fun!
Thank you for saving me!
Well, I think... Are you still going on a journey? Continuing your journey after this?
I am a hero, after all! I gotta go see all the princesses I gotta save in the world!
Excuse me? Huh? It wasn't just me?
Alright, let's go! Happy Birthday!
Well, that's that.
On to the next princess! Let's go!
Many days, intense and fairytale-like scenes, pulverized at the end we have seen
A curtain to fall much too soon, to a world such as this
Still voices taking place right on this field, shadows of many vestiges they aim for
There was a hero who took it all for us, a little journey of memories with you
勇者
The Hero
Lyrics, Music: Ayase
No more pages left in that story, our hero goes into slumber deep
Leaving behind a veil of peace for all, saving the world for us all
The flow of time erases without mercy, any rows of memories and you
Even the traces left in life for now, rustling in time as you said
And yet I'll keep all your hopes, all the words and wishes, courage you won
Still dwell inside me and even now in my heart, keep living through
Odd as it is we share the same path and nothing more to pass, so it should have been
But suddenly I was wondering all those tears rolling down my cheeks, why do they come out and fall?
For I want to find out until we reach right now, if I engage in the journey we went on about again
Though I am no longer walking next to you, one day I know I'll find the truth
Another story unfolds into a journey that alone I set out to
I meet the locals of every town I stop in, they are all recalling the person that you were
Unwavering kindness is something of you, a thing occurring in everything you do
Here and there we can find scattered symbols around, manifesting that all we will prove this
And even back what they mean so one day, I wouldn't find myself alone becoming lonely
And I call to mind every moment of our journey, when I see the signs left in these scenes
Many days, intense and fairytale-like scenes, pulverized at the end we have seen
It was that moment our paths caught meeting, changed 1% of the journey that was me
Even if your courageous steps go into the distance, and for the sake of what everybody can recall
I will bring you along with me into the future shining, taking your hand in mine
And know it all began right at that time, mundane and everyday signs, the moment ignited
And now that you remain, my reflections of those times go on as brightly shining
In these scenes I want to find out until we reach right now, looking back at you standing so proud
Are gently falling right on me without a sound...
I'm perceiving you around...
Story of this journey,
story of the end of hero
forever and ever and ever as you know...
Now a new beginning has to come to be an end
so that you're protected and kept safe...
be these spotting lives around with me
on this journey.
Yay! And then they lived happily ever after.
Or should I say evermore?
But yeah, thank you guys for watching today!
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Make sure you, you know, tell me how it was
using the hashtag.
And of course, since it is my birthday,
I also have to introduce some of my
birthday merch to you guys! Yay!
So we have these items for the
birthday merch this year. Let's see.
Dodon!
Yay! Look! This is my 2025 birthday merch.
Uh, we have a couple of items.
So, the first item, next...
「勇者イナニスの冒険」リバーシブルトートバッグ
"The Adventures of Ina'nis the Hero" Reversible Tote Bag
Okay, with the first item we have the
reversible tote bag.
It has a different design on each side,
so depending on what you feel like having
on the outside,
you can change between the lovely lovely
key visual by Chibi-sensei,
or a very simplified design to be more incognito.
And of course, we have another one. So, next...
タコゲーム！シェイカーアクリルキーホルダー
Takogame! Shaker Acrylic Keychain
We have the Takogame! Shaker Acrylic Keychain.
This one I designed myself.
I wanted to be kind of like, you know,
you can carry it around and it kind of seems
like a little game that you can play
and shake it around and the
Takodachis will shake.
It's a really fun item. And then next...
タコダチケーブルタイ (2個セット)
Takodachi Cable Tie (Set of 2)
We also have the Takodachi Cable Tie,
where you can organize the messy messy chaos
that is cables in your bag, like mine.
But yeah, I hope they're useful.
And last but not least, we have the next...
ミニ「勇者イナ」ぬいぐるみキーホルダー
Mini "Ina the Hero" Plushie Keychain
Yuusha Ina, aka Ninomae Ina'nis the Hero,
this outfit, I call myself the hero.
It's a little cute plushie key chain that you
can carry around everywhere and I will
protect you like a lucky charm. But yeah.
フルセット購入特典
Set Purchase Bonus
And of course, there is a full set bonus
which is going to be a limited... or will
have a limited edition postcard.
But if you buy the set you also get the postcard.
There's a limited set and a not limited set,
so there is that.
And of course, we also have the special
hololive TCG card with the key art.
It's like a thank you bonus for the complete set
of the merch.
You know, this card will only be given to
customers who purchase from the
hololive production official shop.
And this is a Oshi-holomem card which you
can use only one in the game.
I know there's a whole bunch of rules that
you can check out on the website.
Unfortunately, it's only the Japanese version,
there's only Japanese text on it, but you know,
it's kind of like a special limited thing,
so something nice to have.
But yeah, that is it for merch announcement,
etc. I hope you guys enjoyed the live today.
And of course, we still have the omake,
the little NG kind of snippets in the end
and the credits.
So please look forward to that.
Until next time, thank you again everyone!
Have a wonderful rest of the morning,
afternoon, and evening.
I'll see you guys later! Bye-bye!
THUMBNAIL: Ninomae Ina'nis
LOGO: saku (@saku_3)
CHOREOGRAPHY: Miyuki Nishijima
STORY ANIMATION: Animation: tellingbone / Sound Editing & Mixing: Kickback Sound Design
MUSIC: トライフロンティア合同会社 / すくろーす
MUSIC: TryFrontier / Sucrose
山本こーすけ / ふじそば / クックルP
Yamamoto Kosuke / Fujisoba / CookleP
Sound City / 小林彩彩 / 中山太陽 / 堀口彩花
Sound City / Kobayashi Ayasa / Nakayama Taiyo / Horiguchi Sayaka
FILMING & PLANNING: COVER Corp. STUDIO
SPECIAL THANKS: Takodachi
Thanks for watching everyone!!!
I'm really happy that I was able to share this special day with you today!
Did you enjoy the live? Do you like the new outfit?? hehe
Just like the theme of the outfit, I would like to continue to do my bestest with everything I do!
... because that is what a hero... yuusha would do! :D
Thank you for cheering for me! always!! I really wouldn't be here without all your support!!
and of course, BIG THANK YOU to all the staff & creators that could make this happen too!!
I am always indebted to everyone's passion!! THANK YOU THANK YOU & THANK YOU!
It's time... TO GO NEXT!!